Guide to the Working Washington Ephemera Collection
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Working Washington ephemera collection
2012-2015
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5892
5892-001
Working Washington
4.61 cubic feet (6 boxes) plus 1 vertical file, 1 oversized folder, and archived websites
Ephemera collection from a coalition of community groups campaigning for $15 minimum wage in Seattle
Working Washington is a coalition of unions, faith, and grassroots community groups--an outgrowth of Service Employees International Union Local 775--that seeks to unite working people to fight for a fair economy. They were the organization that organized the campaign of fast food strikes that sparked the fight for the $15 minimum wage in Seattle and helped lead the successful campaign to pass a $15 minimum wage in SeaTac.
Banners, picket signs, placards, flyers, advertisements, posters and stickers from Working Washington's campaigns including efforts to combat wage theft, increase the wage for fast food workers (starting in 2012), involvement in the SeaTac minimum wage campaign 2013-2014, and involvement in the Seattle 15Now minimum wage campaign 2013-2015. Other items include a hand drawn coloring book from SeaTac campaign and "wage theft" mock crime scene tape from the wage theft campaign. As well, this collection contains a t-shirt and sign from the Yes! For SeaTac campaign; a ballot initiative that Working Washington for which part of a coalition for a $15 minimum wage on the SeaTac city ballot. The collection includes banners from marches in Bellevue and Olympia. A component of this accession is born-digital photographs from the campaign and digital captures of the Working Washington website, Facebook Page, Flickr gallery, and YouTube channel.
Forms a part of the Labor Archives of Washington
Open to all users. However, an appointment with the Labor Archives curator is required prior to viewing certain items in the collection. Contact UW Special Collections for more details or to request an appointment.
Working Washington$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Minimum wage$zWashington (State); Labor unions$zWashington (State); Labor$zWashington (State); Labor movement$zWashington (State); Posters; Ephemera
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Civic Activism; Seattle; Labor History; Labor Unions
- Placards and posters (Box:oversize 1)
- Folded textile banner (Box:oversize 2)
- Folded textile banner (Box:oversize 3)
- Rolled vinyl banners (Tube:oversize 4)
- Rolled vinyl banners (Tube:oversize 5)
- Demand Delivery Poster (Tube:oversize 6)
  One demand delivery poster presented to management at SeaTac Airport Menzies Aviation, a provider of cargo handling services, by Menzies employees and Working Washington activists. The digital photo collage has quotes from Menzies employees listing their complaints about their working conditions.
  Access by appointment with curator only.
- "It's our Our Airport" bus ads (Tube:oversize 6)
  Three copies of "It's Our Airport" King County Metro bus ads created by Working Washington to demand better working conditions at SeaTac Airport. The posters feature Hosea Wilcox, a skycap at SeaTac, and includes the phrases "Make All Airport Jobs Good Jobs" and "First Class", "Coach Class", and "Poverty Class" with images of the airplane seating areas for the first two classes and the image of Wilcox as the "Poverty Class."
- Placards, posters, and picket sign
- Stickers, coloring books, and other small ephemera (Vf VF)
- Archived Websites
  - Yes! For SeaTac, 2013-2015
  - Working Washington Facebook Page, 2014-2015
  - Working Washington Flickr Page, 2015
  - Working Washington Website, 2013-2015
  - It's Our Airport Website, 2013-2015